《行尸走肉》
大家都后退
Everyone, get back!
快回到你们家里
Get into your houses, go!
瑞克
Rick!
你得后退
You need to get back.
是我们得后退
We need to get back!
快
Come on.
后退
Back!
Get back!
迪安娜  你没事吧
Deanna, you all right?
天啊  天啊
Oh, god. Oh, my god.
不
No!
瑞克  能收到吗
Rick, you copy?
有人吗
Anybody?
救命
Help?
这里  尤金
In here, Eugene!
瑞克
Rick!
很好  你没事  走吧
Good, you're safe. Come on.
那边
There!
好枪法
Good shot.
那边
There!
快走  朱迪思在我家
Come on, I have Judith!
行尸往东边的墙去了
The walkers are flooding into the east wall.
这就说明西边的墙会最先清空
That means that the west wall will be the first to clear up.
我们从那里进去
That's-- that's how we get in.
塔倒了并不意味着...
Just because the tower's down doesn't mean that...
听着  里面的人还活着
Listen, people are still alive in there.
就是这样
This is how it happens.
总是会这样  格伦
And it always happens, Glenn.
我们还在  我们的朋友在里面
We're still here. Our friends are in there,
关心你的那些人
people who care about you.
我怀孕的妻子
My pregnant wife.
你想跑开  心怀恐惧  忘了这一切吗
You just want to run away, be afraid, forget about this?
走吧
Just go.
但你就是这样失去人们的
But that's how you lose people.
甚至是在他们死后
Even after they're gone.
-把她放在沙发上  -楼上
- Put her on the couch. - Upstairs.
左手边第一个房间
First room on the left.
快
Come on.
-在哪  -右边这个
- Where? - This one on the right.
-哪个房间  -进去
- Which room? - Go in there!
山姆  你得关掉音乐  合上百叶窗
Sam, I need you to turn off the music and shut the blinds.
因为那些怪物吗
Because of the monsters?
你待在这里  保持安静
You stay up here and you stay quiet.
会没事的  好吗
It's gonna be okay, okay?
-妈  -亲爱的  努力装一下
- Mom-- - Honey, just-- just try. Just pretend--
装作你不害怕
Okay, just pretend that you're somebody who's not scared.
-努力装一下吧  -好
- Just try. - Okay.
好  我爱你  我爱你
Okay. I love you. I love you.
让我看看
Let me take a look at that.
不  我没事
No, I'm fine.
你谁都不信任  是吧
You don't trust anybody, do you?
那要分人
Some more than others.
但你是我最不信任的
But you're dead last.
至少我们彼此坦诚
Well, at least we're being honest.
我不信任你  但我从没想过你在撒谎
I don't trust you, but I never thought you were lying.
外面怎样了
How is it out there?
满大街都是行尸
They're filling the streets.
你可能脑震荡了
Hey, that's probably a concussion.
快坐下歇会  不然要摔倒了
You should sit down before you fall down.
-我没事  -卡萝尔...
- I am okay. - Carol...
不管我们要解决什么事  都可以等等
Whatever we have to settle, it can wait.
必须等等
It has to.
我觉得他不会回来了
I don't think he's coming back.
你觉得他会回来吗
Do you think he's coming back?
我们可以聊天的  是吧
We can talk, right?
你没必要害怕
You don't have to be afraid.
说话啊
Talk.
外面有受伤的人  我那里还有病人
There's injured people out there. I have patients.
我不应该在这里的
I shouldn't be here.
你们都不应该在这里
None of you should.
那你呢
What about you?
我怎么了
What about me?
在你干了那些事情之后
After the things you've done,
你属于这里吗
you belong here?
没错
Yes.
你以为我干了什么
What do you think I've done?
你杀了人
You've killed people.
我们解放了他们
We freed them,
然后...
and then...
我们不过是准备利用一下剩下的东西而已
we were just going to use what was left.
你来之前并不知道是什么事  对不对
You came here without knowing what this was, right?
不知道摩根把我关在了这里
That Morgan had me here?
他说过他不会放你走的
He said he wouldn't let you go
除非他确定了你不会再杀人
until he was sure you wouldn't kill again.
只是感染了而已
It's just an infection.
我之前闯进了一辆车里
I was breaking into a car
然后被生锈的保险杆割伤了
and cut myself on a rusty bumper.
仅此而已
Just like that.
没什么公平不公平的
It's not unfair or just.
如今没什么是不公平的了
Nothing's unfair anymore.
感染可能不会害死我  也可能会
It might not kill me, but it might.
谋事在人
I've done my part.
成事在天
The world will take care of the rest.
永恒不变
It won't change.
给我看看伤口
Show me the wound.
你生来不是这样的
You weren't born this way.
你变了
You changed.
你能改变的
You can change.
她怎样了
How is she?
不是针对米琼恩  但她在干的事
No offense to Michonne, but whatever she's doing
把我弄得疼死了
hurts like a son of a bitch.
我刚刚把腿部处理好
I just finished with the leg.
看起来那是最严重的...
And that seems to be the worst of--
真是...
Well...
该死
Shit.
已经开始发烧了
Fever's setting in.
她的时间不长了
She doesn't have long.
她清楚接下来会发生什么  对吧
She knows how it happens, right? All of it?
是的  她清楚
Yeah, she knows.
她居然还有心思讲笑话
She's cracking jokes.
瑞克...
Rick...
没有你她逃不掉的
She wouldn't have run.
储备的食物足够我们撑一段时间
We have food to last us a while.
它们迟早会聚起来  汇集到某处
They're bound to cluster up by then, move off to one area.
到那时我会想办法去武器库
When they do, I'll try and get to the armory...
把它们引开
Draw them away.
-用枪声吗  -照明弹
- With guns? - Flares.
我会把大门打开  发射照明弹
I'll open the gate, fire them off...
看能不能把它们引到...
See if I can get them somewhere...
反正引出这里就好
Somewhere that's not here.
你给瑞克的那张设计图...
The plans that you gave Rick...
我仔细看过了
I've been looking them over.
我懂
I get it.
那计划行得通
They could work.
眼下你还这么想吗
Even now?
深信不疑
Even now.
空白处的拉丁文  是什么意思
The latin in the margins, what was that?
那是雷吉在情况很糟时常说的一句话
It was something Reg used to say when things went really, really badly.
我很幸运  米琼恩
I'm lucky, Michonne.
跟家人一起  为了美好的未来而奋斗
Working with my family towards a better future is--
是我的毕生所愿
It's all I ever want
而我也得偿所愿
That's what I got.
我做了自己想做的事
I got to do what I wanted...
直到最后一刻
right up to the end.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想要这个地方运作下去
I want this place to work.
是的  但是那对你有什么意义
Yes, but what does that mean for you?
你自己想要什么
What do you want for you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你最好知道
You better.
罗恩
Ron?
你没事吧
You all right, man?
伊妮德死了
Enid's dead.
我们都死了
We're all dead.
听着  我爸会想到办法的
Look, my dad's gonna figure something out.
-他总是能想到  -胡扯
- He always does. - That's bullshit.
你爸只会害死更多人
Your dad's just gonna get more people killed.
因为他只会那样做
'Cause that's what he does.
他就是那样的人
That's who he is.
你爸是个杀人凶手
Your dad's a killer.
你爸也是
So was yours.
-我们得想办法  -我死了  卡尔
- We need to work this out. - I'm dead, Carl.
我妈死了
My mom is dead.
-我弟死了  -他们没死
- My brother is. - No, they're not.
我们会活下来的
We're gonna make it.
你爸  你们也死了
Your dad-- you're dead, too.
我们都死了
We're all dead.
卡尔
Carl!
-卡尔  -罗恩
- Carl!  - Ron!
-让我进去  卡尔  -罗恩
- Let me in! Carl! - Ron!
卡尔  开门
Carl, open the door!
罗恩  马上开门
Ron, open the door right now!
退后
Back up.
帮把手
Help!
拜托  罗恩  过来
Please, Ron! Come on!
快
Come on!
来了  让开
Here, move.
-小心  -让开
- Watch out! - Move!
这个不够  而且我们得保持安静
We need more, and we need to be quiet.
我去找找还有什么能用的
I'll see what I can find.
-我也去  -帮把手
- Me, too. - Help.
-我来  -里面发生了什么
- I got it. - Hey, hey, what happened in there?
我们在找工具  结果打翻了一个架子
We were looking for tools and knocked over a shelf.
我们听到了叫声
We heard yelling.
是的  罗恩看到它们冲破了门
Yeah, Ron saw them break through the gates.
我们必须逃走
We had to move.
就是这样
That's what happened.
卡尔  我妈卧室有床头柜
Carl, there's nightstands in my mom's room.
我们可以用它们抵住沙发
We can brace the couch with them.
-什么  -你们那时听起来像是在打架
- What? - Hey, it sounded like you were fighting.
是的  但我们是在跟行尸打架
Yeah, but we were fighting them.
卡尔  没事吧
Carl? It's okay?
没事
It's okay.
-听着  我...  -枪给我  枪柄对着我
- Listen, I, uh-- - Hand me the gun, grip first.
-卡尔  对不起  -我知道
- Carl, I'm sorry. - Yeah, I know.
把枪给我
Now give me the gun.
听着  伙计
Look, man...
我懂
I get it.
我爸杀了你爸  但是
My dad killed your dad, but,
有些事你得明白
you need to know something.
你爸是个混账
Your dad was an asshole.
它们把雕像推倒了
They knocked the sculpture over.
噪音引来了更多行尸
All that noise, it's drawing more.
我去照顾她
I'll get her.
不  我还活着
No, it's still me!
抱歉  抱歉
I'm so-- I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I, I'm sorry.
我想看她最后一眼
I-- I wanted to see her one last time.
我以为我能走过来
I thought I could make it.
可我的腿不听计划
My legs had other plans.
过来
Come here.
慢点  慢点
Easy, easy.
你就喜欢乱计划
You and plans.
现在是你的计划了
They're yours now.
从现在起...
From now on...
必须有人陪着你
Someone needs to be with you.
是啊
Y-yeah.
不能是她
It can't be her.
没错
Yep.
我把她放到别的地方去
I'll find someplace else to put her.
瑞克
Rick.
我...
I, uh--
我写了点东西
I wrote something...
给斯宾塞和玛姬
For Spencer, for Maggie.
我一定会送到他们手上
I'll make sure they get them.
你能照顾好他吗
Will you look out for him?
-我会的  -你会像照顾你的人一样
- I will. - Will you look out for him
照顾好他吗
like you look out for your people?
你猜怎么着
Guess what.
他们都是你的人  瑞克
They're all your people, Rick.
全都是
They are.
事情还没有发展成那样
We haven't had a chance to make it that.
但已经是那样了
But that's how it is.
我冲过去帮你不是因为我喜欢你
I didn't run over to help you out there because I like you...
或是因为我认为你是一个好人
Or because I think you're a good man,
一个好父亲...
a good father...
或是因为你能长出一嘴大胡子
Or that you can grow one hell of a beard.
我跑过去帮你是因为你是我们的一员
I ran over to help because you are one of us.
这才是正确的答案
That's the right answer.
瑞克
Rick!
(世界史)
大部分人都跑进自己屋里了
Most people got inside their houses. There's that.
你觉得到此为止了吗
You think this is it?
什么
What?
你觉得这地方完蛋了吗
Do you think this place is over?
不
No.
我觉得我们所有人都应该努力争取
I think we gotta earn it, all of us.
不管是等着  得知大家是否安全
Whether it's waiting, knowing if everyone's safe,
应对此事或者对抗它们
dealing with that, or fighting them.
住在这种地方总得付出相应的代价吧
A place like this has gotta have a price, right?
我们付出的还不够多吗
We haven't paid it already?
显然不够
Apparently not.
感觉亚伯拉罕已经死了
It feels like Abraham's dead.
感觉就是这样
That's what it feels like.
他没死
He's not dead.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我没看到
'cause I didn't see it.
不管你感觉怎么样
Doesn't matter what it feels like.
他还没死  这地方还没有完蛋
He's not dead, and this place isn't over.
我们在这里呢
We're here.
所以我们要做什么  美女
So, what are we gonna do, gorgeous?
我们进屋子  看看另一边的情况
Gonna get in there, see what's happening on the other side.
我们可以用枪把锁崩了
We can shoot out this lock.
我们不应该浪费子弹
We shouldn't waste the bullet.
不需要用子弹
You won't need to.
开锁是我的技能之一
Lock-picking is within my skill set.
你还好吗
You all right?
闭目养神而已
Just resting my eyes.
卡萝尔
Carol?
它们太多了
There's just too many of them.
所有人上楼  快
Everybody get upstairs now!
后退
Back off!
快点  快点
Come on! Come on!
用沙发
The couch!
把楼道封住
Let's block the stairs.
我搞定这个  你去搞定后面那个
I got this one, you get the one behind it.
至少需要两只
We're gonna need at least two.
离他远一点
Get the hell away from him.
他被绑上了  他没有...
He's tied up, he's not--
我说离他远一点
I said get away from him.
这事本可以等等
This could've waited.
应该等等的
It should have.
现在等不了了
Now it can't.
你待在这
You stay here.
看到它们挤进来就叫我
You see anyone squeezing through, you get me.
我们需要床单  足够所有人用
We're gonna need bed sheets, enough for everyone.
要床单干什么
Bed sheets for what?
我们一起去武器库
We all go to the armory.
-怎么去  -我们要把它们开膛
- How? - We're gonna gut these things.
然后披着内脏
Cover ourselves with the insides.
这能掩盖气味  让它们觉得我们是行尸
It'll mask our smell, make them think we're like them.
我以前也干过
I've done it before.
我们保持冷静  别引起它们的注意
We stay calm, we don't draw attention,
就可以穿过尸群
We can move right through them.
它们在房子里  发出声音
They're in the house, they're making noise.
会引来更多行尸
More are coming.
留在这会死的
Anyone who stays here is gonna die.
迪安娜怎么办
What about Deanna?
你不需要用刀
You don't need the knife.
我们可以谈谈
We can talk.
不  没什么好谈的
No, this is over.
我们能比他们好
We can be better than them.
我们本来就比他们好
We are better than them.
杀人就未必了
Not if we kill.
他们逼我们杀人
They made us kill.
我们必须得阻止  我必须得阻止
We had to stop it. I had to stop it.
只要活着  就有各种可能
With life, there's possibility,
即使我们永远不放他出去
Even if we never let him out.
-我会出去的  -即使我们永远不放他出去
- I'd get out. - Even if we never let him out,
他也有可能反省他的所为
he could know what he's done.
-他有可能...  -我不想杀你  摩根
- He could know... - I don't want to have to kill you, Morgan.
你不会的
You won't.
我会的
I will.
你做不到
You can't.
我不会让你杀了我
I won't let you.
外面怎么了
What's happening out there?
它们在涌进来
They're getting in.
我们余下的人
The rest of us...
我们得走了
we're gonna have to go.
-你要是想的话  我可以...  -不
- If you want me to, I'll-- - No.
我没准备好
Not ready.
还没
Not yet.
之后会的
I will be.
很快
Soon.
当我准备好时
And when I am...
我会自己动手
I'll do it myself.
命是我自己的
It's my life.
自己开头  自己结尾
Start to finish.
[拉丁语]
什么意思
What does it mean?
"总有一天  你所承受过的痛苦
"Someday this pain
会有助于你"
will be useful to you."
走吧
Go.
他们需要你
They need you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢你还有信念
For believing.
我依旧有信念
I still believe.
我全搞砸了
I cocked it all up...
但我想明白了
...but I figured it out.
你想要什么
What do you want?
现在该你想明白了
Now you figure it out.
我会的
I will.
很好
Good.
杀出去
Give'em hell.
我们得走了  你先走我随后
We need to move. You, then me.
我会的
I'll do it.
妈
Mom?
你得听我说  好吗
You need to listen to me, okay?
我们不再安全了
We aren't safe here anymore.
只有这么做我们在外面才会安全
Okay, we need to do this so that we can be safe out there.
我们得装得像怪物一样
We need to look like the monsters.
不要  求你了  不
No, please, no.
亲爱的  我们得走了  好吗
Yes, honey, we have to go, okay?
我们必须这么做  山姆
We have to, Sam.
亲爱的  假装你很勇敢
Honey, just-- just pretend you're brave.
好吗  就装一下
Okay? Just make it all pretend.
这都不是真的  你是个不害怕的人
Okay, none of this is real and you're somebody who isn't afraid.
好吗
Okay?
好的
Okay.
为了杀他我会杀了你
I will kill you to kill him
因为我不想再让任何人死了
Because I don't want anyone else to die.
你应该杀了我
You should kill me.
不过你们都会死的
But you're all going to die.
你们不属于这里
You don't belong here.
告诉我你很肯定
You tell me you're sure.
告诉我你知道会发生什么  是什么结局
You tell me you know what'll happen, how it will go.
请让开
Please step aside.
我只说一次
I'm not asking you again.
不
No!
我们必须走了
We have to go.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
罗恩
Ron?
好
Yeah.
-我去带上朱迪思  -瑞克
- I'll get Judith. - Rick.
我在外面不会放弃
I'm not gonna give up out there.
我不会回头  不管发生什么
I will not turn back, no matter what happens.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
求你了
Please?
求你别这样
Please don't.
别哪样
Don't what?
别杀他们
Don't kill them.
你说他们已经死了  你说我已经死了
You said they were already dead you said I was.
你没必要杀我们
You don't need to kill us.
让我们自己死吧
Just let us die.
你说的都是屁话
You are so full of shit!
我就喜欢你们身上这点
You're what I like about people.
塔拉
Tara.
天啊
Oh, god.
-别乱动  -别这样
- Just be still. - Don't.
放下枪
Lower the guns.
很好
Good.
丢过来
Slide them over.
我要枪
I want them.
你不需要她
You don't need her.
没错
No.
我不需要
I don't.
后退
Back.
你在外面活不下去的
You're not gonna make it out there.
走着瞧
We'll see.
妈
Mom?
Mom!
-达里尔  -我看见了
- Daryl? - Yeah, I see.
搞什么鬼
What in the holy shit?
你们为什么不出来
Why don’t you come on out?
到路上来
Join us in the road.
如果你们想反抗
You know, if you want to resist,
耍花招
try something. I mean,
那是你们的自由  我猜
it’s a choice, I guess.
但是我们会消灭你们
But we will end your asses.
把你们从菊花到鼻子撕成两半
Split you right in two, straight through to the sinuses.
所以下来吧
So, come on.
真好
That's great,
一开始就很顺利
it's going well right out of the gate.
现在  第二步
Now, step 2.
交出你们的武器
Hand over your weapons.
凭什么
Why should we?
因为武器不是你们的
Well, they are not yours.
什么
What?
是这样
See...
你们的武器  卡车  卡车里的汽油
Your weapons, your truck, the fuel in your truck,
贮物箱里的薄荷糖
if you got mints in your glove compartment,
座位下的色情片
if you got porn underneath the seat,
座位里的零钱  甚至是座位本身
change in the seats, hell, the seats themselves,
脚垫  地图
the floor mats, your maps,
放在中控台里"应急"的纸巾
little stash for emergency napkins you got there in the console.
-那些东西都不再是你们的了  -那是谁的
- None of those things are yours anymore. - Whose are they?
你们的财产...
Your property...
现在归尼根所有
now belongs to Negan.